<location name="Florence">
<description>
Florence (Italian: Firenze [fiˈrɛntse] ( listen), alternate obsolete form: 
Fiorenza; Latin: Florentia) is the capital city of the Italian region of 
Tuscany and of the province of Florence. It is the most populous city in 
Tuscany, with c. 370,000 inhabitants (1,500,000 in the metropolitan area). 
The city lies on the River Arno; it is known for its history and its 
importance in the Middle Ages and in the Renaissance, especially for 
its art and architecture and, more generally, for its cultural heritage. 
A centre of medieval European trade and finance and one of the 
wealthiest cities of the time,[3] Florence is considered the birthplace 
of the Renaissance; it has been called the Athens of the Middle Ages.[4] 
A turbulent political history included periods of rule by the powerful 
Medici family, religious and republican revolution. From 1865 to 1870 
the city was also the capital of the recently established Kingdom of 
Italy.

The historic centre of Florence attracts millions of tourists each year.
 It was declared a World Heritage Site by UNESCO in 1982. Florence is 
 regarded[5] as one of the most beautiful cities in the world,[6][7] 
 and the impact of its artistic,[8] historic and cultural heritage in 
 the world remains to this day. The city has a major impact in music, 
 architecture, education, cuisine, fashion, philosophy, science and 
 religion. The historic centre of Florence contains numerous historical 
 squares, Renaissance palaces, academies, parks, gardens, churches, 
 monasteries, museums, art galleries and ateliers.

The city boasts a wide range of collections of art, especially those 
held in the Pitti Palace and the Uffizi, (which receives about 1.6 
million tourists a year).[9] It has been the birthplace or chosen 
home of many notable historical figures, such as Dante, Boccaccio, 
Leonardo da Vinci, Botticelli, Niccolò Machiavelli, Brunelleschi, 
Michelangelo, Donatello, Galileo Galilei, Catherine de' Medici, 
Giotto di Bondone, Luigi Cherubini, Antonio Meucci, Guccio Gucci, 
Franco Zeffirelli, Salvatore Ferragamo, Roberto Cavalli, Leonardo 
Bruni, Coluccio Salutati and Emilio Pucci.
</description>
<shortdesc>A must. Beautiful architecture, beautiful art, great coffee shops and food.
The River Arno, Michaelangelo's David, the Duomo, and many expensive shops.
</shortdesc>
<lat>43.766666</lat>
<long>11.25</long>
<img src="Ponte_Vecchio.jpg" alt="The Ponte Vecchio" />
<weather>
<month>
<name>Jan</name>
<meanhigh>10.1</meanhigh><meanlow>1.4</meanlow><meanprecip>73.1</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Feb</name>
<meanhigh>12</meanhigh><meanlow>2.8</meanlow><meanprecip>69.2</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Mar</name>
<meanhigh>15</meanhigh><meanlow>4.9</meanlow><meanprecip>80.1</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Apr</name>
<meanhigh>18.8</meanhigh><meanlow>7.7</meanlow><meanprecip>77.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>May</name>
<meanhigh>23.4</meanhigh><meanlow>11.3</meanlow><meanprecip>72.6</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jun</name>
<meanhigh>27.3</meanhigh><meanlow>14.7</meanlow><meanprecip>54.7</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jul</name>
<meanhigh>31.1</meanhigh><meanlow>17.2</meanlow><meanprecip>39.6</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Aug</name>
<meanhigh>30.6</meanhigh><meanlow>17</meanlow><meanprecip>76.1</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Sep</name>
<meanhigh>26.6</meanhigh><meanlow>14.2</meanlow><meanprecip>77.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Oct</name>
<meanhigh>21.1</meanhigh><meanlow>10</meanlow><meanprecip>87.8</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Nov</name>
<meanhigh>14.9</meanhigh><meanlow>5.5</meanlow><meanprecip>111.2</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Dec</name>
<meanhigh>10.4</meanhigh><meanlow>2.4</meanlow><meanprecip>91.3</meanprecip>
</month>
</weather>
</location>
