<location name="Venice">
<description>
Rome (English pronunciation: /ˈroʊm/; Italian: Roma pronounced [ˈroːma] 
;  Latin: Rōma) is the capital of Italy and the country's largest and 
most populated city and comune, with over 2.7 million residents in 
1,285.3 km2 (496.3 sq mi). The city is located in the central-western 
portion of the Italian Peninsula, on the Tiber River within the Lazio 
region of Italy.

Rome's history spans two and a half thousand years. It was the capital 
city of the Roman Kingdom, the Roman Republic and the Roman Empire, 
which was the dominant power in Western Europe and the lands bordering 
the Mediterranean Sea for over seven hundred years from the 1st century 
BC until the 7th century AD. Since the 1st century AD Rome has been the 
seat of the Papacy and, after the end of Byzantine domination, in the 
8th century it became the capital of the Papal States, which lasted 
until 1870. In 1871 Rome became the capital of the Kingdom of Italy, 
and in 1946 that of the Italian Republic.

After the Middle Ages, Rome was ruled by popes such as Alexander VI 
and Leo X, who transformed the city into one of the major centers of 
the Italian Renaissance, along with Florence.[2] The current version 
of St Peter's Basilica was built and the Sistine Chapel was painted 
by Michelangelo. Famous artists and architects, such as Bramante, 
Bernini and Raphael resided for some time in Rome, contributing to 
its Renaissance and Baroque architecture.

In 2007 Rome was the 11th-most-visited city in the world, 3rd most 
visited in the European Union, and the most popular tourist attraction 
in Italy.[3] The city is one of Europe's and the world's most 
successful city "brands", both in terms of reputation and assets.[4] 
Its historic centre is listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.[5] 
Monuments and museums such as the Vatican Museums and the Colosseum 
are amongst the world's 50 most visited tourist destinations (the 
Vatican Museums receiving 4.2 million tourists and the Colosseum 
receiving 4 million tourists every year).[6]
</description>
<shortdesc>What's there to say. Beautiful. Electric atmosphere and very sophisticated.
The Coliseum, The Vatican, Trevi Fountain, Spanish Steps, Palatine Hill
</shortdesc>
<lat>45.4386111</lat>
<long>12.3266667</long>
<img src="CastelSantAngelo.jpg" alt="Castel Sant'Angelo" />
<weather>

<month>
<name>Jan</name>
<meanhigh>11.8</meanhigh><meanlow>2.7</meanlow><meanprecip>102.6</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Feb</name>
<meanhigh>13</meanhigh><meanlow>3.5</meanlow><meanprecip>98.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Mar</name>
<meanhigh>15.2</meanhigh><meanlow>5</meanlow><meanprecip>67.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Apr</name>
<meanhigh>18.1</meanhigh><meanlow>7.5</meanlow><meanprecip>65.4</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>May</name>
<meanhigh>22.9</meanhigh><meanlow>11.1</meanlow><meanprecip>48.2</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jun</name>
<meanhigh>27</meanhigh><meanlow>14.7</meanlow><meanprecip>34.4</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jul</name>
<meanhigh>30.4</meanhigh><meanlow>17.4</meanlow><meanprecip>22.9</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Aug</name>
<meanhigh>30.3</meanhigh><meanlow>17.5</meanlow><meanprecip>32.8</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Sep</name>
<meanhigh>26.8</meanhigh><meanlow>14.8</meanlow><meanprecip>68.1</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Oct</name>
<meanhigh>21.8</meanhigh><meanlow>10.8</meanlow><meanprecip>93.7</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Nov</name>
<meanhigh>16.3</meanhigh><meanlow>6.8</meanlow><meanprecip>129.6</meanprecip>
</month>

<month>
<name>Dec</name>
<meanhigh>12.6</meanhigh><meanlow>3.9</meanlow><meanprecip>111</meanprecip>
</month>
</weather>
</location>
