<location name="Venice">
<description>
Venice (Italian: Venezia [veˈnɛttsja] ( listen), Venetian: Venexia [veˈnɛsja]) is a city 
in northern Italy known both for tourism and for industry, and is the capital of the region 
Veneto, with a population of the whole Comune of about 270,660 (census estimate 30 April 2009). 
Together with Padua and Treviso, the city is included in the Padua-Treviso-Venice Metropolitan 
Area (PATREVE) (population 1,600,000).

The name is derived from the ancient people of Veneti that inhabited 
the region as of 10th century B.C.[1][2] The city historically was the capital of 
the Venetian Republic. Venice has been known as the "La Dominante", "Serenissima", 
"Queen of the Adriatic", "City of Water", "City of Masks", "City of Bridges", 
"The Floating City", and "City of Canals". Luigi Barzini, writing in 
The New York Times, described it as "undoubtedly the most beautiful city 
built by man".[3] Venice has also been described by the Times Online as 
being one of Europe's most romantic cities.[4]

The city stretches across 117 small islands in the marshy Venetian 
Lagoon along the Adriatic Sea in northeast Italy. The saltwater 
lagoon stretches along the shoreline between the mouths of the Po 
(south) and the Piave (north) Rivers. The population estimate of 
272,000 inhabitants includes the population of the whole Comune 
of Venezia; around 60,000[5] in the historic city of Venice 
(Centro storico); 176,000 in Terraferma (the Mainland), mostly 
in the large frazioni of Mestre and Marghera; and 31,000 live 
on other islands in the lagoon.

The Republic of Venice was a major maritime power during the 
Middle Ages and Renaissance, and a staging area for the Crusades 
and the Battle of Lepanto, as well as a very important center of 
commerce (especially silk, grain and spice trade) and art in the 
13th century up to the end of the 17th century. This made Venice 
a wealthy city throughout most of its history.[6] It is also known 
for its several important artistic movements, especially the 
Renaissance period. Venice has played an important role in the 
history of symphonic and operatic music, and it is the birthplace 
of Antonio Vivaldi.</description>
<shortdesc>
Beautiful medieval city built on a lagoon.  City transit is only by
boat.  Several important festivals, including movie festivals and
Mardi Gras.</shortdesc>
<lat>45.4386111</lat>
<long>12.3266667</long>
<img src="Rialto_Bridge.jpg" alt="Rialto Bridge and the Grand Canal" />
<weather>
<month>
<name>Jan</name>
<meanhigh>6</meanhigh><meanlow>-1</meanlow><meanprecip>58.4</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Feb</name>
<meanhigh>8</meanhigh><meanlow>1</meanlow><meanprecip>53.3</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Mar</name>
<meanhigh>12</meanhigh><meanlow>3</meanlow><meanprecip>58.4</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Apr</name>
<meanhigh>16</meanhigh><meanlow>8</meanlow><meanprecip>63.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>May</name>
<meanhigh>21</meanhigh><meanlow>12</meanlow><meanprecip>68.6</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jun</name>
<meanhigh>24</meanhigh><meanlow>16</meanlow><meanprecip>76.2</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Jul</name>
<meanhigh>27</meanhigh><meanlow>18</meanlow><meanprecip>63.5</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Aug</name>
<meanhigh>27</meanhigh><meanlow>17</meanlow><meanprecip>83.8</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Sep</name>
<meanhigh>23</meanhigh><meanlow>14</meanlow><meanprecip>66.0</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Oct</name>
<meanhigh>18</meanhigh><meanlow>9</meanlow><meanprecip>68.6</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Nov</name>
<meanhigh>11.5</meanhigh><meanlow>4.2</meanlow><meanprecip>87.3</meanprecip>
</month>
<month>
<name>Dec</name>
<meanhigh>6.7</meanhigh><meanlow>0</meanlow><meanprecip>53.7</meanprecip>
</month>

</weather>
</location>
